<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B) Rapid Prototyping (W37) on Social / Business Data Science 2024</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/</link><description>Recent content in B) Rapid Prototyping (W37) on Social / Business Data Science 2024</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Streamlit: Building an Employee Attrition Dashboard</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</guid><description>Corgi working on a Data Science project. 2023. Roman x Stable Diffusion XL
Streamlit has rapidly become a go-to tool for data scientists and developers wanting to turn data scripts into shareable web apps. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore its core features and benefits:
Key Features of Streamlit Simplicity: With just a few lines of Python code, you can have a running web application. No need to deal with HTML, CSS, or JavaScript unless you want to.</description></item><item><title>Streamlit Development &amp; Running Offline</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01.5_streamlit_offline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01.5_streamlit_offline/</guid><description>Streamlit provides an easy and rapid way to turn data scripts into interactive web apps. However, at times, developers may need to ensure that their Streamlit applications run offline. Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple guide to setting up Streamlit in an offline environment using Anaconda and Visual Studio Code (VSCode).
Setup with Anaconda Environment Follow these steps to set up Streamlit within an Anaconda environment:
Install Anaconda &amp;amp; VSCode
Download and install Anaconda.</description></item><item><title>- Real World Data to Online Dashboard</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</guid><description>This session will focus on building interactive online dashboards using real-world geospatial data, with an emphasis on GeoPandas for data manipulation and visualization. Students will learn how to use GeoPandas to read, filter, and manipulate geospatial data, create interactive map-based visualizations, and ultimately deploy their dashboards to the web.
Introduction to GeoPandas Using GeoPandas to analyze geospatial data will be our focus in these notebooks.
GeoPandas GeoPandas and Solutions GeoPandas Hands-on Project GeoPandas Hands-on Project and Solutions GeoPandas Exercises GeoPandas exercises GeoPandas exercises and solutions From Geopandas to Streamlit App 🚀 Simplified version of the analysis - with Folium Plotting App code Deployed App What to do now?</description></item></channel></rss>