<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C) Intro to Unsupervised Machine Learning (W38) on Social / Business Data Science 2024</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/03_uml/</link><description>Recent content in C) Intro to Unsupervised Machine Learning (W38) on Social / Business Data Science 2024</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/03_uml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>- Introduction to Unsupervised ML</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/03_uml/01_intro_uml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/03_uml/01_intro_uml/</guid><description>This session will introduce the principles and applications of unsupervised machine learning (UML). Students will learn about the different types of UML problems, and they will explore some of the most popular UML algorithms, such as PCA, SVD, and NMF.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro to Dimensionality reduction and Clustering
Assignment for the UML
Assignment for the UML Solution
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5</description></item><item><title>- Recommendation and Similarity Search</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/03_uml/02_recommender_simsea_uml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/03_uml/02_recommender_simsea_uml/</guid><description>
In this workshop we are going to learn about recommender systems as a type of UML. Such systems are probably the most widely used and commercialy valuable form of AI today. Specifically we will be looking into collaborative filtering and matrix factorization.
Plan for today Collaborative filtering / SVD recommender using Nomadlist Trips-data in a Notebooks Streamlit recommender-app Notebook(s) Nomadlist Trips Notebook Nomadlist Trips Notebook Solutions Recap Nomadlist Trips Notebook Recap Similarity Notebook Recap Dimensionality Reduction Class UML Exemple cosine similarity App Source code for the app Deployed recommender app Recommended Readings and resources This excellent PyData Talk by the developer of LightFM Recommended Datacamp exercises: Beginner Tutorial RecSys-Course</description></item><item><title>- Introduction to Clustering: K-means and Hierarchical Approaches</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/03_uml/04_intro_kmeans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/03_uml/04_intro_kmeans/</guid><description>This session will introduce the principles and applications of clustering. Students will learn about the different types of clustering problems, and they will explore some of the most popular clustering algorithms, such as K-means and hierarchical clustering.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro Clustering Hands-on Intro Clustering Solutions App NBA Player Injury Replacement Recommender NBA Player Injury Replacement Recommender Streamlit Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5 What Is Machine Learning?</description></item></channel></rss>