<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>A) Introduction to Data Science (W35-36) on Social / Business Data Science 2024</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/</link><description>Recent content in A) Introduction to Data Science (W35-36) on Social / Business Data Science 2024</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>- Welcome Students!</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/01_welcome_ds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/01_welcome_ds/</guid><description>This session will introduce you to the fundamentals of data science, with a focus on Python. We will cover the Python data science stack, essential tools and platforms, software setup, semester overview, and Python 101.
Session 1: Welcome Students! This session sets the stage for your data science journey:
Python Data Science Stack: Dive into Python&amp;rsquo;s core data science libraries and frameworks. We&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered!
Ecosystem Deep Dive: Familiarize yourself with essential tools and platforms, such as Github, UCloud, Google Colab, and Jupyter.</description></item><item><title>- Data Handling and Manipulation</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/02_data_handeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/02_data_handeling/</guid><description>This session will introduce students to the foundational aspects of data handling in Python. Students will learn about the different types of data that are important in data science, and they will explore essential operations like arrange, group-by, filter, select, and join. By the end of this session, students should have a solid understanding of primary data manipulation techniques, setting the stage for more advanced subjects.
Session 2: Data Handling and Manipulation I (Lecture) In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the foundational aspects of data handling.</description></item><item><title>- Exploratory Data Analysis and Essential Statistics</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/03_data_visualization_stat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/03_data_visualization_stat/</guid><description>This session introduces students how to use EDA and some fundemental concepts of statistical methods to uncover patterns, anomalies, and frame questions in data. Students will learn foundational measures and techniques for data interpretation, and they will have the opportunity to apply EDA and statistical methods on datasets through hands-on exercises.
Deep Dive into EDA: Uncover patterns, anomalies, and frame questions. Key Statistical Concepts: Foundational measures and techniques for data interpretation.</description></item><item><title>- Data Visualization in Data Science</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/05_data_visualization_ds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/05_data_visualization_ds/</guid><description>This session will teach you the fundamentals of data visualization in data science. You will learn the importance of effective data visualization, the principles that drive meaningful visuals, and how to use two popular Python libraries for data visualization: Seaborn and Altair.
Foundations of Visualization: Understand the importance of effective data visualization in Data Science and the principles that drive meaningful visuals. Seaborn Mastery: Explore Seaborn, a Python library for intuitive statistical graphics.</description></item><item><title>Mathematics (Brushup)</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/07-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds24/en/m1/01_intro_ds/07-math/</guid><description>How does Math help us? Machines can only understand numbers. For instance, to perform ML algorithms on text and multimedia, they need to be stored in vectors, matrices, and tensors. An example would be the representation of text as a vector of 768 dimensions. Using linear algebra, you can manipulate vectors, matrices, and tensors.
We will focus on understanding the mathematics behind ML algorithms in two dimensions. This tutorial will provide you with an overview of how machine learning algorithms work when applied to higher-dimensional data.</description></item></channel></rss>